Maybe which was recessed a little earlier, and we are on Item 3, which is public input on schedule personal appearances and the audience it wishes to address the council.
Item 4 is considered gender staff is recommending items fire through 10 for the consent agenda.
If you want to know questions, do we have a question to approve items fire through 10?
Thank you for that.
And a second.
Second.
Johnson.
Lewis.
Hi.
Weston.
I'm 11.
I'm a representative plan for the Miami Regional Airport Chief Anderson.
How are you today?
I'm a little nervous.
I'm not a airplane.
I'm going to buy three tickets because being things he's going to wing it, I'm going to wing it.
I'm going to buy four tickets.
I encourage everybody to buy a few tickets.
I'm going to buy ten tickets.
It'll be starting real estate post the year.
I will show what I have to pay for the FAA on the registration airplane.
That's a problem.
Get the registration.
We want to be registered.
Yeah.
We want to be legal.
That's why we're going to pull off on that.
People are brought from the elderly dad.
He's in the table.
Time table.
It's a sign for him.
If they want to know, right, certain by copies of papers saying they're authorized to do this.
We give him copies that weren't certified.
So it's been back before a little bit.
It's just a matter of strain out of the paper.
It might be not going to happen.
We do have our six-year title group of plan.
2018, we're taking a year off.
This year, we've finished two projects.
We did our jet-hard stand.
Which is their completion now.
We've had four.
It's trimmed in.
We're in a carrying page right now before they can paint it.
Finish it up.
What's great because they ain't tied down for the larger ones.
And then we'll be completed very shortly.
So that was just a way to see next year.
The other one is a lighting project.
We're redoing the runway lights, taxiway lights.
Putting in an A-Wass system.
Which is a weather reporting system.
A pile you can call it up on the radio.
And flying in and getting ready to get weather.
There'll be a display there in the terminal.
You can look at weather.
You can call it up on the phone.
You get the weather for that airport.
Which is just a huge proof of our report.
And I like the rap lights, the other one way.
And I gauge over the road going out there for security purposes.
That's how I'm including this project.
And it's, I believe, going to kick off.
Construction.
We have a pretty good structure.
We should start that project.
Next week is what they're looking at.
So we're signing that going to be a great improvement for the airport.
Our next big project 2019 in 2020 is designing and bringing new taxiway.
Our existing, our main taxiway.
takes away off of the parallel of the runway. We closed it this year for one-and-a-half
graduation. There's cracks and all the down on the white contacts away. Some of them
you can put your hand in and you never hit the bottle. We tried to crack seal loads and
just chucked that crack seal up. At least it had her guy filled sand and then sealed
the top of that and obviously it sucked that up and there were just some very major cracks
there. In addition to the damage to the taxiway, by a pay-radio license, it's too close
to the main runway. It has to be an offset. When they put in the new extension to the North
and the taxiway, that's where the whole taxiway should line up. That's where the plan for
the 40-pointable drop-up back and reserve put in the taxiway. The lighting project we're moving
to the wind cone to allow for that. Our next project list is our personal fence. It'll be around
the Northland of the perimeter of the airport. My first flight, I took a while and I was flying with
taxi in the Northland of God's Wild West High. You would say maybe you do something about this.
You know when you people walk across your old home, I'm like, they do well. They come from
this house here over here in the Walmart and they just cut across here for real. I didn't know
it. As we're taxiing out there, we have to stop because there are two people on the taxiway
coming across the runway. It's like right there. Wow. There is a little bar bar fence that
is halfway down between that house here in the North West and people cut across that all
time and we're trying to ramp up and wander that little difficult to watch effectively so we
do want a proper fancy project to help remedy that and keep saving for them for my house. They do
it all out for mine. You have a temporary picture of that chief? What are you doing for that problem,
we have the same fence. We have tried to monitor it a little more but we don't have a
perfect fix. That's why we're pushing to get that printer fancy. Then the last project here is
the open rehabilitation which is the main part here is not. We have the new Jeff had the C man or
so it's pavement. Peyton started to deteriorate a little bit and it gets fogged with cracks up and kicks
up dirt rocks and that's very hazardous for aircraft. Our total private cost for the five
years about 2.8 through FAA funding in our and in total of 2 defa and then the airport crew projects will
this.
city's match on that will be about 285,000 over the next centuries for those brothers, so
this while I'm 10% from to 1A and so.
How's the fuel and project going out there?
Did you wish for me?
Fuel sales.
With the tanker.
Yeah.
The tanker.
We have.
And it's still.
They are interpreted or upgraded, it needed filters and hoses, which we knew when we bought it.
We bought it with discounted price as opposed to buying one of the totally reconditioned
for real.
We are doing that ourselves and saving total of my money.
We went through with some pump service to do that.
They ordered other parts and we are waiting for those coming to put that in service.
We have it yet put in service, we are waiting on that.
Those are the hoses that be changed out and those parts aren't over, it's just matter
get them in the mail.
Could be that.
So, there's 285,000 over 5 years, that's outside of the operational funds that you might need.
Just for management.
Thanks.
Any questions for the chief?
No, sir.
All right.
Thanks a lot.
I appreciate that, Dave.
Item 1.
12 is that date on the fall of site.
Close your question?
Targeted just a little bit of background on it in case some of you weren't on the council
when we started this project so to kind of bring you out of the speed.
The fall of site has been been in 2008 by the county and the use of it was to put some of the
are the majority or all of the flood houses that were bought back by the county and the city.
The debris from those homes were put in that sidewall, some other items.
So, there's a city of courgettes.
In the airport house.
In 2010, the city entered into a mutual access agreement with them where we started sharing
the site with the county and then in 2012, oversight of the site was transferred to the
transfer to the city.
Then what the city has used it for, of course, for the flood houses and a few other houses
that were taken down due to the light and in 2016, the ODQ contacted the city and
asked us to close the site, start the process of closing the site, we negotiated with the
community, add the debris from the real picture site to the fall of site before we closed
it.
What the city's required to do from there is within 120 days of the last deposit to have the site
have covered with a bill and top solo up to two feet.
And then ODQ will come back out and we'll start to find that the site is closed and we have
to monitor the site for three years, for too much settling or changes in the in the contour.
I attached a couple of pictures here to show you this is what the site looked like in 2010
when the county had it.
2011 you can see it started to kind of spread to get any more to the bottom down where
debris is going. 2013 this if you have never been out to the site where what we're responsible
for is contouring this. So this part right here was kind of a high point in the in the
property that had drop off and then another drop off. And what the agreement was through the landfill
process that would then become kind of like a rolling film, mobile and road and road. So go on
to the end. And this is what it looked like in 2015. So where we're at in the process now is we have
got the little picture to breathe out there and we put it in the bill and we have satisfied the contract
that we went out to bid for for topsoil has been satisfied. So we so far put out there,
a lot of 1,500 cubic yards at topsoil and we're going to do a little more pushing on the dirt a little
more contouring. It's going to require some more dirt for us to finish it out and finish out the
project. And that 120 day clock is ticking. Yes, that I maintain good contact with Wes, which is our contact with
WQ and he's been out in the monitoring side. He's been nothing but complimentary about
a progress. He's really pleased with what he's seen. And then the chief is very pleased with our work
and the way that it's the way that it's shaping up also. Okay, the one key thing I wanted, I really appreciate
the history on that because this is not going to an intense message project, close it up and
people see that and think it's just affiliated with what we can believe in the picture.
which was most recent. No, it's not. It was all the way back to 2007 and what the city committed to as part of the 2007.
So it's kind of closing that chapter of our history.
And the bottom thing is that even though it's the briefment of the computer side, there is no chat taken out there in the chat.
No, yes.
So this is the case of the events that I hear in the picture where we're saying it's the label code in the chat.
Chat is taken to a proper distance of the story.
Questions for Christian?
I think it's Christian.
I'm 13.
Bond's favorite day on this flashfire.
That's a little bit.
We have received the notification from Modi.
He cured that the site is substantially demoed and in their eyes kind of ready to go.
We notified Susan Henry, which is our person with the grant.
And looking at a possible December 1st, we can December visit to the site.
And from that point, then that's their call.
What they're going to say that we need to do.
We are, we are to the point where we've got our CMAR not selected because you guys haven't loaded on it.
But our committee met.
We worked out some things we're going to meet with the MCVV for tomorrow to get their recommendation.
We're meeting with the Planning Commission Thursday to get their recommendation.
We will come back to 21st for your CMAR vote for with our recommendation on that.
The RFQ for the architect is ready to go out.
And we don't have to bid that out.
We just send it out and solicit.
And then get responses back.
We've got four that we're going to solicit for our architect.
The Hitch on that is until we sign that final contract with our RFQ.
Any money that we spend on it are not going to be reimbursed.
So we're trying very hard to get it ready to wear.
When they say okay, we can spend the large amount of money to go ahead and contract our architect.
And get started on what we're going.
Other than that, we are more rocking in the lower one.
Is there?
When you say it's not certain money can't be reimbursed.
Is there a maximum amount that we applied for or eligible for?
This is the 538,000 dollars, 50,50.
We have to spend all of it though.
They reimburse us for 50%.
Some of it we will be able to do in a kind.
But like our architect, you know, the contract that you're going to have to pay for them.
We have to wait for that final ready to start before we can get anything reimbursed.
But we know how to do it.
had of the advertising and the things like that. That's okay, but we'll try and wait until they say,
okay, give it a look. And there's the 5.38, they all reimbursed a maximum of 50% of that number,
so 27.5. Yeah, 27.5. That's more than that. That's how we're still looking at the summer.
Art, all the time one hasn't changed, it's going to really depend now on what we can get in and
how quick they can get in to start doing the work and everything. Because at this time, we
started with that final contract to where we can actually start. BQ said you're going to go,
but our our our grant people have to give us our final thing. So they said decimals,
first we can decimals when they could probably implement our site. So if we're fortunate,
and have the same kind of order that we have, they'll be able to incorporate new things like that
There are a few other things related to this site too that we're looking at, of course, that will
summer. Um, we might ask them to hold words or something like that at the drainage line.
One of the things we're talking about right now, that way there would be more of a grassy area with
people, all of the area that can happen that. So the main people said having a loop,
they're putting around which is being the start, not only being styra area, and also that way,
the district to be able to walk back and forth. So maybe in the end, I know there's a concern
of that kind of sparking, especially in the sense where it may that maybe will be utilized,
the Japana parking as well as the parking that we're going to be revitalized and that's on that site.
So that will be kind of tied into the design that we're going to be working with the architect. And then
finally, in working with a VQ, they have identified where we do this. And we'll make sure that where
the location is, the way from that point. In the plunge more in the middle of the lot,
and we are looking at the flashback being more in the north, which is an accolade again, in closer to
the, the parking existing parking lot is, which would be the north west corner. So with the design of
what we have kind of been given in the past is that they have, as anybody give an idea of start to finish
for that timeframe for something like that to be built. But we can't, so we don't know what that
is to judge off of if they said, January 1, you're free to go. We still don't know how long it would take to
build this. The estimated time was about six months. So we would be pushing it into June if we
went to January 1, the start. But that's an estimated time. Hope we can speak it.
So of course, I'm like, I'm on the swimming pool. You'd be able to be the opening, so there's a lot of first.
But we can sample it into October. Because we don't have to worry about why the stars don't have to worry about
treatment or anything like that. It's one of those that we'll be...
you've lost a much longer than you thought for exactly what they could.
Well, I mean, and that would be one of those things where it was,
that last week we had a 78 degree day, and so that I went Facebook,
Splash Paddle, we opened today, and love you, come out and enjoy it.
So, it's not, it's not as regulated, like what the poll is,
where you're open for May, you close in August.
You can hit and miss that, the word, and you can access it at the time of the day.
But would you plan on going back to 21st with the recommendation of our C.A.L.R.?
All right, thanks, L.E.S.
I do have a question for you, Ma'am, that's all.
If you didn't, you didn't just want to stand out there for a second,
but I don't know if that would have anything to do with Splash Paddle.
Okay.
Any new business?
Staff of polls.
Yes, sir.
I'm just going to cut the waste on all of the blindes are equal,
and I've seen it on Facebook, too, that are
our annual shelters that can pass to use and spill a problem.
It's always a problem.
We'll get down, we got down, I think it was Thursday of last week,
and then over the weekend we're back up, we're full again.
So, it's a continual, continual, we stay full, five days out of seven, so it can be.
And we're full, we turned to turn away the animals or what?
We have been fortunate that we've been able to double up,
or we've been able to get my annual alliance, or possibly the welfare,
the animal welfare, and adoption agency, and get some out to them,
to where we can jockey some around.
At this point in time, there have been a couple of times
that someone's come into surrender in animal,
and because we try to keep at least one open, so, okay,
so, if you get a vicious animal, we can get them in there,
we've had to turn them away, but today, we have never had to,
an animal at large, a vicious animal, or anything like that,
we've never had to turn them away.
So, even if you're turning away, it's the render, it's come back in four days or longer.
It's called, yeah, you're not to call.
And when we say that, we also will give them the Miami animal alliance,
and we will tell them about the animal adoption,
animal welfare and adoption agency, and we also tell them about
the idea, because many of us sometimes, we have to take something for them.
So, we don't just say, don't we will take it and not give them any other options
who try to help them out, so.
That's some of the animals, are you receiving the animals outside of the city?
No, start.
Okay.
Not at all.
So, I noticed that the county has brought on an additional, another one at Miss Speaks,
which I'm careful here, but I thought they brought on another individual to help with animals outside
in the county.
In some point, somebody asked, are we taking on animals as they, okay, that's just what?
not only do we not take on animals that are not that are outside the city, but if you are
so rendering an animal, it must be someone that lives inside the city that's very very
okay, that's one of those one of those animals.
Someone was in commerce and then when it comes to rendering, we'll take it because it's taxpayer
to dollar. So we try to keep it. That's what makes sure that's clear.
Yes. Okay. Now it's standing.
The 16 is mayor and council committee announcements, and announcements.
We got a parade coming up in a couple of weeks.
So low-refanned hay can business, say, and we have a parade Saturday at five that are in
state parade.
Anything else?
Well, there's a championship Saturday, so there you go, that's Saturday, it's Saturday.
I mean, OSU got robbed, it's that's pretty wrong.
Okay, that was great game.
All that now is to sit in a few occasions, anything else besides getting robbed?
I actually have a few things more to talk about. Kevin Jerry, I thought I'd just bring this up.
I'm not putting on the spot, but next week, Jerry A is hosting some public meetings about their first
relics. That's very important. I think we've all been brief about it.
We're still in home there. We've been tentating involved with that process.
On November 14th, in Langley at 16th, and then November 15th, again in Langley at 10th,
and both of those are going to get the GRDA center that's right by the hand.
And then, 6 p.m. at 1 p.m. at 15th, so they're having three different
different public meetings about that. Again, there were 14, 6 p.m. in Langley, November 15th, Langley at 10th, and then
grow at 16th. And I don't know if you're going to have any additional, but if you like the most
one of these, and why I'm not being more than happy to find a place for me. I think this is important
enough to a lot of people here in town, but they probably don't have to hear what's going on. So you might
want to ask that word along. We'd be happy to host it if you wanted to. So I feel appreciate you're being here
and for the record, you're going to want to be very close to the GRDA. A lot of the things we talked
about today, improving our electric system, similar working on the development projects GRDA's been there.
Helping us out by the disc. So we have some issues, but we also are developing very good relationship with GRDA
and those areas. So I think the relation is very important, because that's for about the next 20, 25 years
how that answer would be offered for the benefit of the organization. So I want to mention that.
I'll also want to mention that this year we're getting into politics. These are already for
We're going to be, if I say, we, a lot of city employees are going to be involved as you
will think to try.
In the past few years, I think that if a community is open and I have that, I think last year
I've had work toward the end of the season, it mentioned that some additional health that
they got.
I think a lot of us have a lot.
We thought it was only going to be the collective bargaining units that we've had, another
we're open up for a lot of people.
So, this is going to be a lot of us on our own time working on working on Asian trading.
I think we're all looking forward to that.
But I just want to mention that because we're doing another organizational meeting this Thursday,
getting very close to high time for that since we're having a whole days and a lot of people
are helping us with that growth.
So, I just want to put in a word there.
Oh, I want to also mention some of you may have been asked about the grant program that
we have for sacreds, for socials and I was made aware today that we shouldn't know about
the end of the year.
We've got those grants and that program will be very soon, but one of the six weeks before we
have been here, but we're beginning to work from the sake that we get more on that very quickly.
So, since we'll let you know the word we are very optimistic, I think we've all talked
about the rule on that.
I think the last time I heard, I think we have that 120 out of the nation, as it was significant.
And unfortunately not everybody's going to get out there, but I think I think everything was
a little bit of a lot of sacreds.
So, with the grant.
Day and I was just for the benefit of the viewers, those people that were turned down or didn't
get approved in a prior cycle.
So, if you were not approved this cycle, you'll probably be in the front of the line next
time.
I'm assuming we've all signed in the world, so, fine, okay, so that's what we're working with there.
Our first meeting in December, since we're not sure how many study sessions we're going to
get.
We're going to get a plan, our first meeting in December, to give you an update on how this project
is going to be sitting in December, probably we've gone to talk about some change out, building
the solar, we're running into change orders, and we talked about that significantly today that
we want you to know about a relevant dance and not after the fact of 62-year-old building.
So, we can change what we run into interesting things about this building, nothing has been
a direct, drastic or dramatic right now, but then also by that time we're going to have a pretty good
idea of what the offices are going to be like and how it's started to fall into place.
Then a nature project that we just want to let you know, if you have any questions about
now it's going, we intend to stand quite a bit of a comment on our first meeting on December.
Talking about, I'm even flushing one who might everybody, the City Office will be closed this Friday for that.
and stay. And I just wanted to thank Tyler and I, Howard, Kristen, and we'll leave our
Christie and Alicia. We had just kind of these quick updates, but these are projects
that we've been taking in a more than a matter of their time. They're very difficult and
very complex projects. And they've all been on top of it for very much and a lot of times
we don't take the time to thank them for a lot of the work that they do, but it's really
really appreciate that. And the other employees that do a lot of good work too,
they do this all for them tonight. And a lot of them have to do this too.
So those are the best ones I've ever pulled for me.
All right. Any questions for Dean?
Okay. That leaves item 18, which is a gentleman. We have most children,
most children. And a second.